AYAN SRIVASTAVA

I am an adaptive person with quick learning qualities. I am very good at getting along with people, in my work environment. I have experience in testing software and automating tests, security, and compliance aspects. Working in a highly competitive environment, driven by vision.



x ayansrivastava081@gmail.com



Gurgaon, India

9005893123

in linkedin.com/in/ayan-srivastava-99b22b1b2

EDUCATION

B.Tech Mechanical Engineering Vellore Institute Of Technology (VIT)

07/2018 - 05/2022

Overall CGPA - 7.81

CBSE 12th Board

Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 2 Kanpur UP

04/2017 - 03/2018

Overall Percentage-75.2%

CBSE 10th Board

Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 2 Kanpur UP

04/2014 - 03/2015

Overall CGPA - 9.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Program Associate Trainee Cognizant Technology Solutions

03/2022 - Present

Pune, Maharastra

Achievements/Tasks

- Working on Functional Testing, Java and Selenium.
- · Allocated with mini-projects like automation and manual testing.
- Solely responsible for testing the full fledge application.

Project Management Intern Radar Soft Technologies

08/2021 - 12/2021

Pune, Maharastra

Achievements/Tasks

08/2020 - 06/2021

- Managing and coordinating between clients and the technical team for website and mobile app development.
- Having scrum calls with clients and generating "Scope of Work", (Handled 2 foreign clients also).
- · Handled 4 projects and made them successful.

Curation And Management head

Fraternity of Young Innovators

VIT Chennai

Tasks

- Led a team of 42 members.
- Planning and executing events for the club.
- Arranged and managed events for our club, in collaboration with Yuvaa, Under25, Prepbytes and many more.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Adjustable Focal Length Eyeglasses (08/2021 - 01/2022)

The idea solves the problem faced by people using the progressive lens, people facing fluctuating eye-power issues. The product works on a rack-pinion mechanism and comes with two types of lenses, one concave and another convex.

CERTIFICATES/TRAININGS

MySQL (2021)

PERSONAL TRAITS

- Good with communication and team building skills.
- Ability to work as an individual as well as in group.
- Highly motivated and eager to learn new things.

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

French

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Volunteer Work

Problem Solving

Travelling

Music

AYAN SRIVASTAVA

I am an adaptive person with quick learning qualities. I am very good at getting along with people, in my work environment. I have experience in testing software and automating tests, security, and compliance aspects. Working in a highly competitive environment, driven by vision.



x ayansrivastava081@gmail.com



Gurgaon, India

9005893123

in linkedin.com/in/ayan-srivastava-99b22b1b2

EDUCATION

B.Tech Mechanical Engineering Vellore Institute Of Technology (VIT)

07/2018 - 05/2022

Overall CGPA - 7.81

CBSE 12th Board

Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 2 Kanpur UP

04/2017 - 03/2018

Overall Percentage-75.2%

CBSE 10th Board

Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 2 Kanpur UP

04/2014 - 03/2015

Overall CGPA - 9.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Program Associate Trainee Cognizant Technology Solutions

03/2022 - Present

Pune, Maharastra

Achievements/Tasks

- Working on Functional Testing, Java and Selenium.
- · Allocated with mini-projects like automation and manual testing.
- Solely responsible for testing the full fledge application.

Project Management Intern Radar Soft Technologies

08/2021 - 12/2021

Pune, Maharastra

Achievements/Tasks

08/2020 - 06/2021

- Managing and coordinating between clients and the technical team for website and mobile app development.
- Having scrum calls with clients and generating "Scope of Work", (Handled 2 foreign clients also).
- · Handled 4 projects and made them successful.

Curation And Management head

Fraternity of Young Innovators

VIT Chennai

Tasks

- Led a team of 42 members.
- Planning and executing events for the club.
- Arranged and managed events for our club, in collaboration with Yuvaa, Under25, Prepbytes and many more.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Adjustable Focal Length Eyeglasses (08/2021 - 01/2022)

The idea solves the problem faced by people using the progressive lens, people facing fluctuating eye-power issues. The product works on a rack-pinion mechanism and comes with two types of lenses, one concave and another convex.

CERTIFICATES/TRAININGS

MySQL (2021)

PERSONAL TRAITS

- Good with communication and team building skills.
- Ability to work as an individual as well as in group.
- Highly motivated and eager to learn new things.

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

French

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Volunteer Work

Problem Solving

Travelling

Music